Alex DeVincenzo

Rocky Mount, VA 24151

(321)-352-2211 alex.devin91@gmail.com

Summary

Electrical engineering graduate from Lund Technical University in Sweden. I worked part time as a supplemental instruction leader at Lund Technical University parallel to my studies. I was the main student representative of the Electrical Engineering class in the University's leadership board. I have previous experience as a product test engineer at a security camera manufacturing and testing company, and as a software implementation analyst with a SaaS company.

Work Experience

Full Stack Software Engineer, NBC Sports

As a Full Stack Software Engineer working as a web developer for a golf video streaming and subscription website, my duties encompass the complete development lifecycle of the platform. I design and implement responsive front-end interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to ensure an engaging user experience. On the back-end, I develop make sure our data is managed in the most effective way with Java and C#, manage databases to handle user data and subscription details, and integrate video streaming capabilities. Additionally, I collaborate closely with UX/UI designers, manage API integrations for content delivery and storage, and ensure the website's performance, security, and scalability. My role also includes troubleshooting issues, performing code reviews, and staying updated with the latest web technologies to continuously enhance the platform.

Software Implementation / QA Analyst, HRSoft

I gather customer requirements and perform hands-on configuration of software products using the agile / SCRUM methodology to conceptualize, document and execute project plans. Defect finding, logging, fixing, and preparing Implementation/QA test plans of several different clients is one of my many responsibilities. I create and modify customer compensation statements using SQL, java, and Jaspersoft iReport. I also design and modify customer home pages using HTML and CSS.

Maitland, Florida — October 2018 - Current job

Product Test Engineer, Axis Communications AB

Continuation of developing hardware and software solutions for a new method of testing the infrared lighting of various different model security cameras. Lund, Sweden — May 2018 - August 2018

Intern, Axis Communications AB

Worked developing hardware and software solutions for a new method of testing the infrared lighting of various different model security cameras, and wrote a bachelor's thesis on the subject.

Lund, Sweden — February 2018 - May 2018

Student representative in Program Leadership Board, Lund Technical University

Helsingborg, Sweden— August 2015 - February 2018

Supplemental Instruction leader, Lund Technical University

As a supplemental instruction leader, I guided students in discussion and collaboration to overcome difficult problems which were typical and representative of problems they faced within their education.

The topics covered:

- Physics
- Electrical circuit theory
- Calculus
- Programming
- Digital systems
- Algebra

Helsingborg, Sweden — August 2016 - February 2018

Education

Lund Technical University- Campus Helsingborg, Sweden

Electrical Engineering and Automation



2018. Alex DeVincenzo and Marcus Christensson, "New Concepts for Infrared

https://www.eit.lth.se/sprapport.php?uid=1147

Projects

Smart Rain, a student-built automatic terrarium hydration system which utilized an Arduino Uno and several different sensors and input components to automatically hydrate a terrarium environment.

Certifications

- Performance Tuning and Optimizing SQL Databases
- Querying Data with Transact-SQL
- Intellipaat MS SQL Server Training

Skills

Programming:

Java, C# .Net, SQL, Python, TestStand, Matlab, Jaspersoft iReport Studio, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TortioseSVN, GitHub, handlebars.

Development of PLCs (beginner), development of electrical circuits, transducer technology, analog and digital electronics, arduino, raspberry pi, IoT integration of sensors.

General:

Microsoft word, microsoft excel (advanced), powerpoint, microsoft outlook, microsoft OneNote, public speaking, group leader, excellent written communication, creating of test case / test plan documentation, smoke testing, UAT (User Acceptance Testing), functional testing, regressional testing, identification and analysis of defects within a web application

References

la Rosenlind: Institution of food technology at Lund University- Civil Engineer and Lecturer +46 76 397 90 01 (Swedish number)

ia.rosenlind@food.lth.se

Erik Fors: Axis Communications AB - Manager, Production Test Group +46 46 272 3651 (Swedish number)

Erik.Fors@axis.com

Christian Nyberg: Lund University Lecturer - University Lecturer and Program Leader for Computer Engineering +46 46 222 9174 (Swedish number) christian.nyberg@eit.lth.se

Mats Lilia: Lund University Lecturer - University Lecturer and Program Leader for Electrical Engineering +46 42 35 67 12 (Swedish number) mats.lilja@iea.lth.se